SILVINA VARELA

CONTACT INFO

varelasilvina@gmail.com (+54 11) 66 66 60 41 github.com/silvina-varela linkedin.com/silvinavarela

ABOUT ME

Full Stack Developer with experience building web applications with PERN and MERN stacks. I have 10+ years of experience working with teams and managing projects. I'm resourceful, organized and I have a keen eye for detail that allows me to quickly identify errors.

SKILLS

JavaScript - TypeScript - HTML - CSS

React - Redux

Node - Express - Sequelize

PostgreSQL - MongoDB

Agile Methodologies - Scrum - CI/CD - Git

Figma - Adobe InDesign - Photoshop - Illustrator

Problem solver - fast learner - self-motivated

LANGUAGES

English (C2 Proficient)

Spanish (Native)

Italian (B1 Intermediate)

Portuguese (A1 Basic)

French (A1 Basic)

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Buenos Aires, Argentina

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer | Plan21 Foundation, Dec. 2022-now *Voluteer position*. I create prototypes in Figma and develop new features for a web application using React.

Freelance Copyeditor, Proofreader & Typesetter | 2016-now

Eterna Cadencia Publishing House is a long-term client that has trusted me with many projects (between 1 and 3 a month). I have also worked for other publishing houses and for independent authors.

Senior Book Editor | Biblos Publishing House, Jan. 2016- June 2022

As editor at a Social Sciences and Philosophy publishing house I was responsible for delivering around 5 books on time each month. I oversaw the entire production process. I lead a team of copyeditors and designers. I managed the schedule. I was the main link between the authors and the publishing house. I would occasionally negotiate publishing contracts.

Freelance Translator (English <> Spanish) | 2016-2021

I translated books, articles and websites.

Teaching Assistant | University of Buenos Aires, 2017-2019

Ad honorem position. I assisted the teacher with grading homework and tests. I helped students with activities.

Assistant Book Editor | Eterna Cadencia Publishing House, 2013-2016 I assisted the editor in many tasks, including copyediting, proofreading and typesetting. I was responsible for managing the production of e-books.

WEB DEVELOPING PROJECTS

E-commerce project, Sept.-Oct. 2022

Worked with an agile team. Managed the GitHub repository and JIRA. Lead the team of frontend developers. Developed features using React.js, MUI and Tailwind.

SPA, Sept. 2022

Developed a SPA using JavaScript, React/Redux, pure CSS, NodeJS, Express, Sequelize and PostgreSQL.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Developing Certificate

Henry Bootcamp (2022)

Degree in Editing and Book Publishing

University of Buenos Aires (2012-2016)